

Senior Development Analyst seeking roles in Software Development in salesforce marketing cloud and IT Production Java support



Current Designation: Senior Development Analyst Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: Accenture Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Delhi / NCR, Gurgaon, Noida

Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: software developer, application programming, production support, agile methodology, incident management, software troubleshooting, jira, linux, Salesforce, salesforce markeing cloud, ampscript, html, css, java

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 18-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

B.Tech. (CS /IT) with 5+ years of experience in software Development & maintenance and CRM Application Production Support. Presently associated with Accenture, Gurgaon as Senior Application Development Analyst.

Exposure handling application deployment, incident management, problem management, service request and troubleshooting, debugging and finding root cause of the problem in live production and staging environment.

Exposure of working in Agile Methodology with DevOps Mindset for adidas CRM application in JAVA and Linux .

Experience in Salesforce Marketing Cloud development as well as administration, with hands on knowledge on Studio, Builders and Administration for Adidas and Microsoft.

Work Experience

Accenture as Senior Development Analyst

Jan 2020 to Till Date

Project Name: Microsoft Digital Team size: 8

Project Overview: As part of this project we are taking care of Microsoft Digital operation like building transactional and promotional emails for Microsoft products. We are also responsible for campaign Go live of the emails.

Tool & Technologies Used: Amp script, HTML, CSS, Salesforce marketing cloud Email studio, automation studio, Journey Builder.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Designing email templates and delivery for transactional and promotional emails in DEV and Production environment.
- Working on Production Go live of the emails and newsletters of Microsoft products.
- * Resolving the issue raised in Production in Environment by client and by quick fix ensure the delivery as per client standard.
- * Peer review of the emails build by other team members.

Home Credit India as Technology Analyst

Oct 2019 to Jan 2020

Project Name: Home Credit Application Support Team size: 6

Project Overview: We are taking care of Home credit application responsible for acquiring new consumer for commodity

loan at POS (Paperless) and ACL application for cash loan.

Language: Core Java/J2EE 1.6, SQL

Tool & Technologies Used: Oracle DB , Linux OS, Jenkins, Splunk Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Working on Issue related HC IN application in pre prod and production environments as per defined SLA to provide the resolution and Fix the issue.
- * Engaging with DEV team and IT Admin team for deployment and Production related activities.
- * Setting up alerts and Dashboard in Splunk to monitor the application API performance.
- Attending Regula KT Session to further enhance the functional Knowledge in Home credit Landscape.

Infosys Limited as Technology Analyst

Dec 2014 to Jul 2019

Key Projects Handled

Project Name: Oracle Transport Management Application

Client: Kraft Heinz Corporation

Duration: Oct 2015-Aug 2016 Team size: 8

Project Overview: OTM application will read the order payload provided by third party SAP stored in messaging queue and SAP Order Itegration application will transform this text order payload into a XML format file to provided it to another third party application

IDE: Eclipse

Language: Core Java/J2EE 1.6, SQL

Tool & Technologies Used: Oracle DB, FileZilla, Linux OS

Roles and Responsibilities: Worked as software developer to make changes in SAP order Integration application as specified in SRS document. Also helped the testing team to during testing and involved in GO live of the application.

Project Name: CRM- Consumer Acquisition Client: Adidas Corporation

Duration: Aug 2016 - July 2019 Team size: 16

Consumer Acquisition Track Overview: As part of this track we are taking care of CRM applications responsible for acquiring the adidas consumer into system through various channels like ecom, retail, offline data collections. Adidas consumer portal is used to manage the user details for different markets and brands. This is SSO (SingleSign On) integrated environment having a three way integration with PF (Identity management system) DemandWare and SCV (REST web services). CP is responsible for subscription of newsletters and enable the users for registration, signin ,updating details in the system.

Tools Used: Jenkins, Eclipse, Postman, Splunk, Soap Ui, Appdynamics, PingFederate, Oracle DB, Jira. Application Server and Language: Tomcat, Apache, Linux OS, Java, docker. Roles and Responsibilities:

- * Working on Issue related to CRM application in staging and production environments as per priority defined and to complete the resolution of the ticket within defined timelines of P3,P2,P2 ticket.
- * Documenting the P1 Incident raised in CRM areas with quality standard and providing feedback to the client and defining proactive measure taken to avoid such incidents in future.
- * Providing the consumer's data to client requested for campaign and targeting, improving the performance of the application and to give insight into reporting and data analysis.
- * Setting up the alerts in instana and Splunk to capture the issue in CRM applications and to notify the concerned team /party
- * Co-ordinating with third party and other team for patching of the servers, resolving the high priority incident in timely manner.
- * Co ordinating with DEV team and infrastructure team for the deployment and clear the backlogs in CRM areas.
- * Training the Juniors resources to have proper understanding of the track, helping teams members to resolve the urgent task on time, assigning task to new resources based on priority and capabilities.
- * Creating How To Pages in Jira Confluence for daily repetitive task and also submitting cases for automations to do complete these task manually.
- * Helping other dependent team to gain basic knowledge of the tools and application being used in CRM to remove the dependency to increase the productivity in CRM area.
- * Handling weekly service report with client to provide understanding on high priority issue.

Consumer Engagement Track Overview: As part of this track, we are targeting adidas consumer base through various channels like email, message and push notification using sales force marketing cloud (ExactTarget). We are sending real time emails like account creation, forgot password, subscription email as well as batch emails for targeted campaign & behavioural emails like abandoned cart and browse.

Tools and Technologies: Salesforce Marketing Cloud (ExactTarget) Roles and Responsibilities:

* Working with DEV team to make go live of emails, triggered sends and Journeys for different adidas market

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from Kamrah Institute of Information Technology in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience	
Java 1.6 / 1.7		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Jenkins, Docker , Linux OS		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MobaX ,Postman , SoapUI ,Splunk		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Appdynamics ,instana. Amp script , SOQL		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
MYSQL, ORACLE		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Rest Services, SOAP		2019	3 Year(s) 0 Month(s)	
Salesforce Marketing Cloud		2020	2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
Journey Builder, Audience		2020	2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
Builder , Content builder , Email Studio		2020	2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	
Mobile Studio		2020	2 Year(s) 2 Month(s)	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Hindi				

Projects

Project Title: Microsoft Digital Operation Center

Client: Microsoft Corporation Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Jan 2020 - Till Date Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: As part of this project we are taking care of Microsoft Digital operation like building transactional and promotional emails for Microsoft products. We are also responsible for campaign Go live of the emails.

Tool & Technologies Used: Amp script, HTML, CSS, Salesforce marketing cloud Email studio, automation studio, Journey

Builder.

Project Title: CRM- Consumer Acquisition

Client: Adidas Corporation Nature of Employment: Full Time

Duration: Aug 2016 - Jul 2019 Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: As part of this track we are taking care of CRM applications responsible for acquiring the adidas consumer into system through various channels like ecom, retail, offline data collections. Adidas consumer portal is used to manage the user details for different markets and brands. This is SSO (SingleSign On) integrated environment having a three way integration with PF (Identity management system) DemandWare and SCV (REST web services). CP is responsible for subscription of newsletters and enable the users for registration, signin ,updating details in the system.

Project Title: Oracle Transport Management Application

Client: Kraft Heinz Corporation

Nature of Employment: Full Time Duration: Oct 2015 - Aug 2016
Onsite / Offsite: Offsite

Project Details: OTM application will read the order payload provided by third party SAP stored in messaging queue and SAP Order Itegration application will transform this text order payload into a XML format file to provided it to another third party application

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Category: General Job Type: Permanent

Physically Challenged: No Employment Status: Full time